**Save up to 50% on Car Insurance** [Get Started](https://smartfinancial.com/get-fast-quote.html?aid=77&cid=3425)

* Insurance Quotes
* About us
* [Talk to an Agent **855-214-2291**](javascript:void(0))

[](javascript:void(0)) [Get Started](https://smartfinancial.com/get-fast-quote.html?aid=77&cid=3425)

* About us

* **855.214.2291**

**Privacy Policy**
==================

SmartFinancial Privacy Policy
=============================

Last revised: May 24, 2023

Your privacy is important to us. This Privacy Policy (the “Privacy Policy”) governs the use of your Personal Information (as defined below) in connection with any websites, online services, and/or applications owned or operated by SmartFinancial.com Insurance LLC, an Ohio LLC (“we,” “us,” “our,” or “SmartFinancial.com”), including, without limitation, in connection with:

\- the websites currently located at [SmartFinancial.com](https://smartfinancial.com/) and any other website owned by us upon which this Privacy Policy is linked (collectively, the “Site”); and

\- any other services, transactions, engagements, or other interactions you have with us (all of which are collectively referred to as the “Services”).

This Privacy Policy explains what information we collect about you, how we use or disclose such information, how to exercise any rights you may have with respect to your Personal Information (including any rights to opt-out of certain uses of your information), and the safeguards we have in place to reduce the risk of unauthorized access and use.

Please carefully read this Privacy Policy, which is part of our [Terms of Use](https://smartfinancial.com/terms-of-use), before using our Site and/or Services. If you do not agree with the [Terms of Use](https://smartfinancial.com/terms-of-use) and/or the Privacy Policy, you must refrain from using our Site and/or Services. By accessing or using our Site/Services you agree to our use of your information consistent with the [Terms of Use](https://smartfinancial.com/terms-of-use) and this Privacy Policy.

**1\. INSURANCE DISCLAIMER**

We are not an insurance company or an insurance agent. We help connect individuals and businesses with companies that may be able to provide insurance products. We do not charge individuals or businesses to submit inquiries regarding obtaining insurance through our Site/Services, instead, we receive a payment from the companies with whom we connect potential buyers such as insurance agents, insurers, and third-party insurance service websites (such websites and their operators referred to herein as “Insurance Services”).

**2\. PRIVACY POLICY CHANGES**

This Privacy Policy is subject to change. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy frequently for any revisions or amendments. Such changes to this Privacy Policy will be posted on the Site and will be effective immediately upon posting. You will be deemed to have been made aware of and have accepted the changes by your continued use of the Site or Services.

**3\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT** 

**a. Personal Information**

When you view content on our website, we automatically collect PII about your computer hardware and software. This information can include your IP address, browser type, domain names, internet service provider (ISP), the files viewed on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, clickstream data, access times and referring website addresses. We use this information to provide general statistics regarding use of the Websites. For these purposes, we do link this automatically-collected data to other Personal Information such as name, email address, address, and phone number.

We collect information that personally identifies, relates to, describes, or is capable of being associated with you (“Personal Information”), including:

* Personal Identifiers (e.g., name, date of birth, social security number, driver’s license number, IP address, login username & password)
* Characteristics of Protected Classifications (e.g., gender, sex, marital status, sexual orientation)
* Contact Information (e.g., mailing address, email address, phone number, fax number)
* Commercial Information (e.g., motor vehicles owned/leased, use of motor vehicles, residence information, insurance claim history, desired insurance products)
* Financial Account Information (e.g., credit card number, checking account number)
* Consumer Reports (e.g., criminal and driving history reports, credit reports)
* Internet or Other Electronic Network Activity (e.g., browsing history, search history, other information regarding your use of our Site/Services that can be associated with you)
* Professional or Employment-Related Information (e.g., occupation)
* Education Information (e.g., highest level of education obtained)
* Health Information (e.g., tobacco use, medical history)
* Device, browser, and location information, such as computer make and model, browser type and version, IP address (to determine geographic location for marketing purposes, in compliance with applicable laws).

This information can be provided to us by you through our websites or webforms an/or information we collect automatically when you use our websites and webforms.

Inferences drawn from the above categories of Personal Information that relate to your preferences, characteristics, psychological trends, predispositions, behavior, attitudes, intelligence, abilities, and aptitudes.

The types of Personal Information we collect about you may vary based on how you use the Site and/or Services and your role in the insurance marketplace (e.g., consumer, agent, insurer).

From time to time, and in order to provide you with the best service possible, we may use your information for automated decision making.

**b. Consumer Report Notice**

In some cases, insurance agents, insurers, and Insurance Services may need to obtain additional background information about you. For example, consumer reports (including credit reports) may be ordered in connection with your insurance application. These reports provide information that may assist in determining your eligibility for insurance and the price you may be charged. Consumer reports may also be used for updates, renewals, or extensions of insurance. Insurance companies may also obtain and use a credit-based insurance score based on information contained in your consumer report. Insurance agents, insurers, and Insurance Services may use a third-party service provider in connection with the development of your insurance score and rate quote. By providing information to us for use in obtaining an insurance quote, you give your express consent for insurance agents, Insurers, Insurance Services, and associated third-party service providers with whom we share your Personal Information to obtain and use a consumer report as described in this paragraph.

**c. Usage Data**

We automatically collect information in connection with the actions you take on the Site and in connection with using the Services (“Usage Data”). For example, each time you use the Site, we use a log file to automatically collect your IP address, the type of web browser you use, the type of device you use, your device’s operating system, your Internet Service Provider, the pages you view, referring and exit pages, the date and time of your visit, and the number of clicks to, from, and within the Site. We use this information to improve the performance and functionality of our Site and Services, and to better understand how individuals interact with our Site and Services. If this information is capable of being associated with you, directly or indirectly, we treat it as Personal Information. If this information is not capable of being individually associated with you, we treat it as Usage Data.

**d. Call Recording**

We and/or our Service Providers (as defined below), may record all calls and retain the content of all text messages or other written/electronic communications between you and us and/or our Service Provider, regardless of whether we make the call to you or you make the call to us. By communicating with us, you consent to such recording and retention of communications.

**e. Session Recording**

We and/or our Service Providers (as defined below), may monitor and/or record and retain the content of all activity, clicks, and keystrokes on our owned and affiliated websites for informational and quality control purposes. By continuing to utilize our website and its content, you consent to such recording and retention.

**4\. HOW WE COLLECT INFORMATION**

**a. Voluntary Disclosure**

We may ask you to provide us with Personal Information when you register with the Site/Services, submit an inquiry form, complete a survey, communicate with us (online or offline), sign-up for a newsletter, and at other times. You are not required to provide us your Personal Information; however, if you choose not to provide the requested information, you may not be able to use some or all of the features of the Site or Services or we may not be able to fulfill your requested interaction.  

**b. Third-Party Data Sources**

We collect Personal Information from third-party data sources such as insurance agents, insurers, Insurance Services, consumer reporting companies, and data brokerage companies. This Personal Information may be appended to Personal Information we have already collected from or about you.

**c. Cookies**

We use cookies (a small text file placed on your computer to identify your computer and browser) to improve the experience of the Site and Services, such as saving your preferences from visit to visit to present you with a customized version of the Site. Many web browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, certain features of the Site or Services may not work if you delete or disable cookies.

We use the following types of cookies:

* Essential Cookies. These Cookies are required for the operation of our Sites (for example, to enable you to log into secure areas of our website or use a shopping cart). These Cookies enable you to move around the Sites and use their features. Disabling these Cookies will encumber the Sites’ performance and may make the features and service unavailable.
* Session Cookies: Session cookies keep track of you or your information as you move from page to page within the Site and are typically deleted once you close your browser.
* Persistent Cookies: Persistent cookies reside on your system and allow us to customize your experience if you leave and later return to the Site/Services. For example, persistent cookies may allow us to remember your preferences.
* Analytics and Customization Cookies: Analytics cookies help us understand how our Site is working and who is visiting our Site. We may use these types of Cookies to ensure that visitors can easily find the information they are looking for on our websites. Google Analytics is one tool we use and you can learn more by reviewing Google’s [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?fg=1).
* Functionality Cookies: These Cookies are used to recognize you when you return to our Sites. This enables us to personalize our content for you, greet you by name, and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region).
* Advertising Cookies: These Cookies record your online activities, including your visits to our Sites, the pages you have visited, and the links and advertisements you have clicked. One purpose of this is to help make the content displayed on our Sites more relevant to you. Another purpose is to allow us and our service providers to deliver advertisements or other communications to you that are designed to be more relevant to your apparent interests. When we and our service providers do so, this also involves partners such as publishers, data management platforms, and demand-side platforms that help to manage the data. For example, if you look at one page on one of our Sites, we may cause an advertisement to be delivered to you, on our Sites, or on other sites, for products referenced on that page or for similar products and services. We and our service providers and partners may also append other data to information collected by these Cookies, including information obtained from third parties, and share this information with third parties for the purpose of delivering ads to you.

Depending on the circumstances, we may use cookies to collect Personal Information, Usage Data, or both.

Some cookies may be placed by third parties such as Google, Facebook, Twitter, or LinkedIn. Personal Information collected by third-party cookies is governed by each third-party’s privacy policy.

Your acceptance of cookies is not required for visiting our website.

Most internet browsers accept cookies automatically. If you do not wish this to be so, you may set up your browser so that it will inform you about the setting of cookies so that you may permit this only in individual cases; or that you refuse to accept cookies for certain cases or on a general basis; or that you activate the automatic deletion of the cookies when you close the browser. In addition, you may at any time delete cookies that have already been set by using an internet browser or other software programs.

Many devices and browsers give you the option to manage and/or disable cookies and other online tracking technologies. To opt-out of the use of these technologies, you can change your browser options to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting cookies. To assist you, we compiled directions for some commonly used browsers and devices in the table below. Keep in mind that not all devices and browsers are the same so the methods described below may not work for your browser, browser version, or device and may change at any time. We encourage you to refer to the relevant instructions for your particular device or browser.

Before you dive in, please note, if you opt out of the collection and use of information via cookies and other tracking technologies, you may still see customized advertising displayed by advertising networks from which you have not opted out. In addition, your opt-out will not prevent any advertising network from displaying advertising that is not customized to you and your interests and, consequently, may be less relevant to you. You will need to make such choices on each browser and device you may use to visit our websites and webforms.

* **Disabling Cookies in Browsers.** When you elect to opt-out on a website, including our websites, an opt-out cookie is placed on your device. Then when you visit the same website, the opt-out cookie tells the website you opted out. This means that blocking all cookies may then prevent the websites from operating as expected and may also prevent your consent choices from being stored. This may mean that if you opt-out and then block cookies, we may not know about, or be able to honor, your opt-out. You should also be aware that blocking cookies on your computer will not affect your consent choices on a different device, such as a mobile device. You may want to keep this in mind when determining your browser cookie settings. For more information on how to disable cookies on the most common browsers see below.
* **Google Chrome (Google Support):**
    1. At the top right, click “⋮” icon, and then Settings.
    2. At the bottom, click Advanced.
    3. Under “Privacy and security”, click Site settings and then Cookies.
    4. Turn Allow sites to save and read cookie data on or off.
* **Apple Safari (Apple Support):**
    1. On Mac:
        * Safari > Preferences, click “Privacy”
    2. On iOS:
        * Settings > Safari, then turn on “Block All Cookies”
* **Mozilla Firefox (Mozilla Support):**
    1. Click the menu button “☰” and select “Preferences”.
    2. Select the “Privacy & Security” panel and go to the “Cookies and Site Data” section
* **Microsoft Edge (Microsoft Support):**
    1. More button “⋯” > Settings.
    2. Select “View Advanced Settings”.
    3. Under “Privacy and security”, click Site settings and then Cookies.
    4. Under “Privacy and Services” > “Cookies”

**Other Options for Disabling Online Tracking.** Blocking cookies in your browser may not prevent cross-site tracking of your online activity using other online tracking technologies. In addition to managing your cookie settings for your browser, you can opt-out of tracking directly with the businesses that operate the tracking technologies. To opt-out of certain analytic tracking by our service providers visit the links below:

**Helpful Links:**

* Google Analytics: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout
* Bing: https://about.ads.microsoft.com/en-us/resources/policies/personalized-ads, http://choice.microsoft.com/

**Do Not Track.** Some web browsers may transmit “do not track” signals (go here to learn more). Web browsers may incorporate or activate these features differently, making it unclear if users have consciously activated them. As a result, we do not take steps to respond to such signals.

**d. Online Behavioral Advertising**

We may work with third-party advertisers, search providers, and ad networks (“Advertisers”) to learn more about you and show you ads or other content that we believe would be relevant to you. Advertisers may collect and use information about your use of the Site or Services as well as other websites and services. These companies may use cookies and other online tracking technologies to collect and use your information. We and/or Advertisers may also append other data to the data collected by Advertisers to create an interest profile of individual users. We try to retain and analyze data in a way that anonymizes it, but it is possible that we may collect or use Personal Information as part of our online behavioral advertising activities. Our Privacy Policy does not cover any use of information by an Advertiser. Advertisements may be shown via the Site, the Services, or on third-party websites. You can visit the Network Advertising Initiative website at [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) or the Digital Advertising Alliance’s website at [www.digitaladvertisingalliance.org](http://www.digitaladvertisingalliance.org/) to learn more about Internet advertising companies and how to opt out of their information collection.

**e. Information from Advertisements and Insurance Services**

If you arrive at the Site via an advertisement (e.g., banner ad) or an Insurance Service, we may collect information regarding the advertisement or Insurance Service with which you interacted and your interactions (e.g., item clicked, date and time)

**f. Tracking Pixels and Clear GIFs**

We employ software technology that enables us to track certain aspects of a user's visit to the Site. This technology helps us better manage content on the Site by informing us what content is effective, how consumers engage with the Site, and how consumers arrive at and/or depart from the Site. The software typically uses two methods to track user activity: (1) "tracking pixels" and (2) "clear gifs." Tracking pixels are pieces of executable code that are embedded in a web page that track usage activity including which pages are viewed, when they are viewed, and how long the pages are viewed. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with unique identifiers which are embedded in web pages and email messages that track whether or not a user has viewed a particular web page or email message. User activity information may be associated with additional information about a user's session, such as IP addresses and the type of browser used, and Personal Information, if provided by the user.

If you arrive at the Site by "clicking through" from another website, then certain information about you that you provided to that other website, such as the terms you were searching that led you to the Site, may be transmitted to us and we may use it. You should review the privacy policy of any website from which you reached the Site to determine what information was collected by that website and for what purpose(s) you agreed that website could use that information. We may retain information about you provided to us by other websites, and will only use it in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Such information may be associated with other Usage Data or Personal Information.

**g. Google Analytics Advertising Features**

We utilize certain Google Analytics tools to improve the Site experience for our users, but also to aggregate the characteristics and browsing habits of our users, on an anonymized basis, to provide products and services that are more tailored to our users.

**h. Social Media Widgets**

The Site may include social media features, such as the Facebook, YouTube, LinkedIn, and Twitter widgets. These features may collect information about your IP address and the pages you visit on our Site as well as other Personal Information. A cookie may be set to ensure that a feature properly functions. Your interactions with social media features are governed by the privacy policies of the companies that provide them.

**5\. HOW WE USE AND SHARE INFORMATION**

**a. Generally**

We use Personal Information for internal purposes, such as to

* Provide you with the Site and Services;
* Process or complete transactions you requested;
* Improve the Site and Services, including customization and personalization;
* Communicate with you Notify you of our or third-party products and services via mail, email, telephone, and/or text messaging;
* Market our or third-party products and services to you;
* Communicate with you about the Site, the Services, and other matters via mail, email, telephone and/or text messaging;
* Perform marketing and non-marketing analytics;
* Operate information security and anti-fraud programs;
* Perform day-to-day business operations such as accounting, bookkeeping, and legal compliance;
* Respond to governmental and other legal requests; and
* Compile information and analyses to enhance the customer experience and improve our business. 
* Develop, operate, improve, deliver, maintain and proetect our services, including webistes and webforms.
* Enhance our services and your experience with them by using information we collect automatically by cookies and other technologies.

**b. Testimonials**

If you provide a testimonial, we may post it publicly on the Site or in other advertising material. By providing a testimonial, you give us permission to use it in any manner and for any purpose, including in marketing and advertising communications, without compensation to you.

**c. Service Providers**

From time to time, we may establish a relationship with other businesses that we believe are trustworthy and that we believe have privacy practices consistent with ours that may include corporate affiliates (“Service Providers”). We contract with Service Providers to provide certain services to us, including:

* Online hosting and maintenance;
* Marketing and promotion design and management;
* Facilitating communications;
* Payment processing;
* Collection of accounts;
* Management of access to services;
* Business analytics (marketing and non-marketing);
* IT and network administration such as data storage and management, website hosting, and data security;
* Professional services as legal and accounting;
* Identity and contact information validation; and
* Day-to-day business operations such as courier services, facilities management, and document destruction vendors. 

We only provide our Service Providers with the information necessary for them to perform these services on our behalf. Each Service Provider is expected to use reasonable security measures appropriate to the nature of the information involved to protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. Service Providers are prohibited from using Personal Information other than as specified by us. We share the following types of Personal Information with one or more Service Providers: personal identifiers; characteristics of protected classification; contact information; commercial information; financial account information; consumer reports; internet or other electronic network activity; professional or employment-related information; education information; health information; and inferences drawn from the above categories of Personal Information that relate to your preferences, characteristics, psychological trends, predispositions, behavior, attitudes, intelligence, abilities, and aptitudes.

**d. Third-Party Selling**

We sell your Personal Information to third-party companies who want to advertise and market products or services likely to be of interest to you, or to provide you with special offers and opportunities because of your relationship with us. For example, we may sell your Personal Information to insurance agents who may be able to provide the type of insurance you are interested in obtaining or Insurance Services that may obtain and present additional insurance options. In the past twelve months we have sold the following types of Personal Information with one or more third-party companies for their marketing purposes: personal identifiers; characteristics of protected classification; contact information; commercial information; financial account information; consumer reports; internet or other electronic network activity; professional or employment-related information; education information; health information; and inferences drawn from the above categories of Personal Information that relate to your preferences, characteristics, psychological trends, predispositions, behavior, attitudes, intelligence, abilities, and aptitudes.

The information we share with advertisers and other third parties and the information you provide directly to such advertisers and other thirdparties is subject to each advertiser’s or other third party’s privacy policy. Please read each advertiser or third party’s policgty to learn more information about their collection practices and the choices ou can make about how they collect and use your personal information. Please note, an advertiser may keep the information we share witht hem (that you provided to us through our websites and webforms) whether or not you elect to purchase their services. The agreements we have with those advertsers and third parties that partner with us require them to secure any personal information (personal data) we provide them, limit how they use such information, and comply with nationa, state and other applicable privacy regulations. Data obtained through the short code program will not be shared with any third-parties for their marketing purposes.

**e. Email Marketing**

We may use your Personal Information to market products or services likely to be of interest to you, or to provide you with special offers and opportunities, via email. With respect to commercial email communications from us, you may opt out of these emails via a link in the footer of all commercial email messages.

**6\. SECURITY**

We recognize the importance of safeguarding the confidentiality of your Personal Information. Accordingly, we employ commercially reasonable administrative, technical, and physical safeguards to protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access, disclosure, and use. Even with these safeguards, no data transmission over the Internet or other network can be guaranteed 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect information transmitted on or through our Site and Services we cannot, and do not, guarantee the security of any information you or we transmit on our Site or using our Services, or that you or we transmit over any other electronic network and you accept any associated risk.

**7\. BLOGS & FORUMS**

Our Site and/or Services may contain features such as blogs, forums, message boards, or other public-facing message systems. If you use one of these features, your comments, including any Personal Information you share, will be viewable to other users and the public. You use such features at your own risk. We are not responsible for the Personal Information you share using such features or any consequences that result therefrom.

We reserve the right, but are under no obligation, to remove any comments from such features that we believe, in our sole discretion, constitute defamation, libel, slander, obscenity, pornography, profanity, hate speech, discrimination, or otherwise offend other users or our brand.

**8\. OTHER WEBSITES**

Please be aware that third-party websites accessible through the Site or Services may have their own privacy and data collection policies and practices. We are not responsible for any actions, content of websites, or privacy policies of such third parties. You should check the applicable privacy policies of those third parties when providing information through linked websites.

**9\. COMPLIANCE WITH LAWS AND LAW ENFORCEMENT**

We cooperate with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We may disclose Personal Information, Usage Data, and any other information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties if, in our sole discretion, we believe it is necessary or appropriate to respond to legal requests (including court orders, investigative demands, and subpoenas), to protect the safety, property, or rights of ourself, users, or any other third party, to prevent or stop any illegal, unethical, or legally actionable activity, or to comply with law.

**10\. OTHER TRANSFERS**

We may share Personal Information and Usage Data with businesses controlling, controlled by, or under common control with us. If we are merged, acquired, or sold, or in the event of a transfer of some or all of our assets, we may disclose or transfer Personal Information and Usage Data in connection with such transaction.

**11\. HOW LONG WE RETAIN YOUR DATA**

We retain your Personal Information for as long as we have a relationship with you. We also retain your Personal Information for a period of time after our relationship with you has ended where there is an ongoing business need to retain it. This includes retention to comply with our legal, regulatory, tax, and/or accounting obligations. Generally, we retain Personal Information until you ask us to delete it, or otherwise in accordinace with applicable law and our internal data retention policies

**12\. CHILDREN’S PRIVACY**

The Site is not intended for children under the age of 18 and we do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of 18. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received Personal Information from a child under the age of 18, we will delete such information from our records.

**13\. OPT OUT**

You have the right to opt out of receiving marketing from us by emailing us at [service@SmartFinancial.com](mailto:service@SmartFinancial.com) If you opt out of marketing you will still receive transactional messages, such as responses to your questions. If you opt-out of receiving marketing communications from our business partners with whom we have shared your information, you will still receive marketing communications from us and any other business partners with whom your information was shared. If you do not wish us to track your location, you can turn off the GPS location or push notifications on your phone or personal computer through your local settings.

**14\. CONTACT US**

If you have any questions about our Site, Services, or this Privacy Policy, please email us at [service@SmartFinancial.com](mailto:service@SmartFinancial.com). You may also send us a letter to the following address:

SmartFinancial.com  
Attn: Privacy Dept.  
4041 MacArthur Blvd, Suite 210  
Newport Beach, CA 92660

**15\. EUROPEAN VISITORS**

In connection with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) applicable in the European Economic Area (EEA), we eliminate or limit the use of cookies and similar technologies with visitors from the EEA (excluding our corporate website available at www.SmartFinancial.com, which continues to use cookies for all users unless opted out (see more information below)). Specifically:

* If you visit a third-party site that uses our services, we will not place any cookies on your device unless you have provided your consent and were provided with notice of our privacy practices and your ability to opt-out at any time.
* We will not seek your consent to use cookies in this instance, though the advertiser or their website publisher may do so.
* If you visit one of our websites, we will only place limited third-party cookies, such as those made available for analytics purposes by Google and Bing. In this case, we will only add these after you indicate your consent. If you do not consent, then no cookies will be written to your device.
* If you do not consent or opt out, you will still be able to use our websites, but certain functionality may be limited. To enable this feature, we use third-party tools to determine your geographic location; if these tools indicate that you are in the EEA, then we treat your visit as above. If you feel that you are subject to GDPR, but we have nonetheless used cookies in connection with your visit without consent (which may be due to a failure of the third party geolocation tools, your use of a proxy server, your location outside of the EEA at the time of your visit, or some other factor beyond our control) please notify us at [service@SmartFinancial.com](mailto:service@SmartFinancial.com) and make sure to include any relevant details so that we can ensure proper treatment of your data under GDPR.

**16\. ADDITIONAL CALIFORNIA CONSUMER RIGHTS**

The California Consumer Privacy Act ("CCPA") gives California residents certain rights to access and delete their "Personal Information," and to opt out of the sale of their Personal Information. The CCPA also requires businesses to disclose in their privacy policies information about how they collect, use, and share Personal Information. This section of the privacy policy contains the disclosures we are required to make and summarizes the rights that California residents have under the CCPA.

For purposes of this section, the term "Personal Information" means Personal Information under Cal. Civ. Code 1798.140(o) as amended from time to time. To the extent that any other provision of this Privacy Policy conflicts with a provision of this section, the provision in this section controls as to California residents.

**a. Right to Know**

You have the right to request that we provide you (i) the categories and/or specific pieces of Personal Information we collected about you; (ii) the categories of sources from which your Personal Information was collected; (iii) the business or commercial purpose for which we collected your Personal Information; and (iv) the categories of third parties with whom we shared your Personal Information. If we sold or disclosed your Personal Information to third parties, you also have the right to request that we provide you (i) the categories of Personal Information we collected about you; (ii) the categories of your Personal Information we sold to third parties; (iii) the categories of third parties to whom we sold your Personal Information; and (iv) the categories of your Personal Information we disclosed to third parties.

Please note that we are not permitted to provide access to specific pieces of Personal Information if the Personal Information is sensitive or creates a high risk of potential harm from disclosure to an unauthorized person such as financial account information, health information, social security numbers, or driver’s license numbers. If we withhold specific personal information because of its sensitivity or risk, we will inform you.

**Categories of Information Collected, Disclosed or Sold in the Past 12 Months**

The below table discloses the categories of Personal Information that we have collected in the past 12 months from the effective date of this Privacy Policy. For each category of Personal Information, the table identifies:

Whether we have sold to a third party, or disclosed for a business purpose, the category of Personal Information; and the categories of third parties to whom the information was disclosed or sold. The table does not include Personal Information provided to us by partners or other customers in a business-to-business context.

| Category of Personal Information Collected | Sold or Disclosed? | Category of Third Parties to Whom the Personal Information was Sold or Disclosed |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **Identifiers**, including your name, name, IP address, email address, phone, address | Disclosed | We have disclosed for a business purpose this category of Personal Information to Service Providers |
| **Customer records information**, including signature, bank account number, address, | Disclosed | We have disclosed for a business purpose this category of Personal Information to Service Providers |
| **Characteristics of Protected Classifications** | Not Sold or Disclosed |     |
| **Commercial Information**, including records of services that you have purchased in the past | Disclosed | We have disclosed for a business purpose this category of Personal Information to Service Providers |
| **Internet or Other Network Activity Information**, including information about how you interact with our website | Disclosed | We have disclosed for a business purpose this category of Personal Information to Service Providers |
| **Geolocation Data** | Not sold or Disclosed |     |
| **Professional or Employment-Related Information**, including your job title and organizational affiliation | Disclosed | We have disclosed for a business purpose this category of Personal Information to Service Providers |

**b. Right to Deletion**

You have the right to request that we delete any Personal Information we have collected about you. Please understand that we are not required to honor a deletion request if we need the information to complete a requested or reasonably anticipated transaction, prevent security incidents or fraud, enable internal uses that are reasonably aligned with your expectations, comply with legal obligations, or perform other functions permitted by law.

**c. Exercising your Rights to Know and Deletion**

You may exercise your Rights to Know and Deletion by calling us at 855-214-2291 or completing the form on our [CCPA Request Page](https://smartfinancial.com/ccpa-opt-out). Please be specific in your request and provide sufficient information to allow us to locate your Personal Information in our systems based on your request. We will retain a record of your request, including a deletion request, in accordance with law. Additional information about our timeframe for response and identity verification is available on our [our CCPA Request Page](https://smartfinancial.com/ccpa-opt-out).

Request information about our collection, use, and sharing of their information (a "Request to Know"), including:

the categories and specific pieces of Personal Information we have collected about them;

the categories of sources from which we have collected their Personal Information;

the business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling their Personal Information;

the categories of their Personal Information that we have sold; and

the categories of third parties with whom we have shared, disclosed for a business purpose, or sold their Personal Information, and which categories of Personal Information we have sold to which categories of third parties.

We will not discriminate against users for exercising these rights. We may charge users different prices or provide different levels or quality of goods or services, if the difference is reasonably related to the value of their data. We may also offer financial incentives for the collection, sale, or deletion of your Personal Information. In addition, some Personal Information is essential for us to provide the Services. For example, we cannot provide you with an insurance quote without first collecting some Personal Information about you. In such instances, your refusal to provide the necessary Personal Information will result in the inability to use our Service.

You may exercise your Rights to Know and Deletion by calling us at 855-214-2291 or completing the form on our [CCPA Request Page](https://smartfinancial.com/ccpa-opt-out). Please be specific in your request and provide sufficient information to allow us to locate your Personal Information in our systems based on your request. We will retain a record of your request, including a deletion request, in accordance with law. Additional information about our timeframe for response and identity verification is available on [our CCPA Request Page](https://smartfinancial.com/ccpa-opt-out).

**d. Right to Opt Out, Correct Inaccuracies**

You have the right to direct us not to sell your Personal Information to third parties. You may exercise your Right to Opt Out by calling us at 855-214-2291 or completing the form on [our CCPA Request Page](https://smartfinancial.com/ccpa-opt-out). Please provide sufficient information to allow us to locate your Personal Information in our systems.

Please contact us at [service@SmartFinancial.com](mailto:service@SmartFinancial.com) if you would like to request access to the PII that we have collected online from you, or to correct factual errors in such information.

**e. Non-Discrimination Notice**

We will not discriminate against you for exercising your rights under the CCPA or this Privacy Policy.

**f. California “Do Not Track” Disclosure**

Do Not Track is a web browser privacy preference that causes the web browser to broadcast a signal to websites requesting that a user’s activity not be tracked. At this time, our Site and Services do not respond to “do not track” signals.

**g. California Site Ownership Disclosure**

Under California Civil Code Section 1789.3, California residents are entitled to the following information: The provider of the Site is SmartFinancial.com Insurance LLC, 4041 MacArthur Blvd, Suite 210, Newport Beach, CA. 92660. To file a complaint regarding the Site or to receive further information about the Site, please contact us. You may also contact the Complaint Assistance Unit of the Division of Consumer Services of the Department of Consumer Affairs in writing at 1625 North Market Blvd., Suite N 112, Sacramento, California 95834 or by telephone at (800) 952-5210.

**h. Right to Non-Discrimination**

Should you wish to exercise your rights as a resident of California, we will not discriminate against you by showing you different products or services based solely upon your request. Kindly note, however, if the advertisers require additional data or information from you before providing quotes, rates, or other information, exercising your California rights may limit the number and range of advertisers who are displayed in response to your request.

**i. Do Not Sell My Personal Information**

Some of our sharing activities may be a “sale” of personal information under California law. For example, when we share information we collected automatically from you with advertisers in order to create consumer profiles and present our advertisers’ products and services to you. Subject to certain exceptions, as a California resident, you may opt-out of the “sale” of your personal information at any time by taking the following actions:

* For information collected automatically through cookies and similar tracking technologies change your browser settings to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting cookies. To learn more, read Cookies and Other Technologies.
* For all other information, if you wish to put on file with us your preference to opt-out of our sharing of your personal Information with third parties for such third parties’ direct marketing purposes or to find out more about your opt-out rights, please submit your request through our Do Not Sell My Personal Information form.

**j. Shine the Light**

California residents may, no more than once per calendar year, request from us information about our disclosure of certain categories of personal information to third parties for direct marketing purposes. To be valid, requests must be submitted to us at in our Privacy Center and select the “Shine the Light Request” option from the drop down menu. We will provide you within 30 days of receiving your request, a list of the categories of personal information (also known as personal data) disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year and the names and addresses of the third parties.

**k. Minors**

Visitors under 16 years of age are not permitted to use and/or submit their personal information at any Site. We do not knowingly solicit or collect information from visitors under 16 years of age. We encourage parents and guardians to spend time online with their children and to participate in and monitor the interactive activities of their children. The CCPA and Children's Online Privacy Protection Act imposes certain requirements on website operators that have actual knowledge that they collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 years of age. If we learn that personally identifiable information of persons less than 13 years of age has been collected without verifiable parental consent, then we will take the appropriate steps to delete this information. To make such a request, or if you have any questions or concerns about the Privacy Policy for the website or its implementation, please contact us at: [service@SmartFinancial.com](mailto:service@SmartFinancial.com).

**17\. Nevada Residents**

Subject to certain exceptions, some of our data sharing practices may be considered a “sale” of your personal information under Nevada Revised Statutes 603A. Nevada residents may opt-out of the “sale” of personal information covered under the statute, by exercising your cookie consent options as detailed in Cookies and Other Technologies or by submitting your request through our Do Not Sell My Personal Information form or call us at 855-214-2291.

**18\. Retention of Your Personal Data.**

We will retain your Personal data only for as long as necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy and to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our legal agreements and policies. We will also retain Usage Data for internal analysis purposes.

#### The Smart Way to Shop  
For Insurance.

* **Call 24/7 for a free quote**  
    855-214-2291
* **Have questions?**  
    info@smartfinancial.com

#### Insurance Quotes [Insurance Quotes](https://smartfinancial.com/)

#### About us [About us](https://smartfinancial.com/)

#### Information [Information](https://smartfinancial.com/)

© 2024 SmartFinancial.com Ins LLC DBA SmartFinancial Insurance. All rights reserved. SmartFinancial Insurance is a digital insurance comparison engine, providing real-time rates and insurance services in all 50 states through its relationships with carrier and agency partners.  
As part of our ongoing effort to provide you with the best possible service, SmartFinancial and its Service Providers may monitor and/or record and retain all activity on this website and its applicable links, for informational and quality control purposes.
